Hi, in this lesson, you will learn how to use voice transcribing tool and conversations
in chat GPT.
So you will see how to talk the chat GPT instead of typing, how to save your time, how
your voice can become text and how to keep it natural, hands-free flow while you work
in alerting something.
So let's start with talking chat GPT.
And doesn't matter, you use desktop or mobile application, adjust, open, chat GPT in your browser,
you will have access to these features, to dictate feature and use with smart features.
So when you use dictate feature, chat GPT first listens you and then transcribe your
voice and replies.
So just like talking to real calling partner, you can describe your problems, ask for
help, or explain your code idea and everything by voice.
You shouldn't type and spend your time.
So when it's when it's better to use this feature, I want to use it because I need to enable
my microphones, I will just explain you what is the best use cases for it.
Worth, worth, best for some discussion topics or exploring ideas or asking questions,
sources and writing along pieces of code along pieces of sentences.
Yeah.
It's great for moments when you want to talk through a concept or bug you facing.
For example, you have some error, you can quickly record whatever you have and ask GPT.
Okay, give me ideas, how can I fix or what costs can be solved.
Or you can, for example, when you learn, you can ask why or how questions about the frameworks
is really easy.
You can ask, okay, explain me the difference between the reality and view JES or how I can or
what features they have.
So it's really useful.
You can brainstorm project structure or some naming ideas.
It's what I do really often when I need to know how to name a variable or how to better
names the application on my file, I ask GPT, give me five ideas, how to name file for
the loader or file for a forum and give a bit context, okay, what this file will do.
I can also discuss some best practices or compare some solutions.
Okay, you also have, on the other hand, the voice conversations and it's a bit different.
It's kind of a real time conversation with your strategy, it's full voice chat.
So you speak, chat GPT, listen to you and then answer and then you again can say something.
So that's real voice conversation is really natural.
It's perfect when you away from a keyboard like walking or cooking or thinking out loud,
you can just run the voice mode, put your phone on the desk, doing something, just speak
to chat GPT.
It's really worked good when you learn some information or when you just have some problems
and you want to have one conversation with chat GPT about asking some follow-up questions,
brainstorming and ideas.
So the pro tip I can give you when you're using these tools is speaking short, try build
the clear sentences and do some poses between ideas.
This really helped chat GPT understand your intent and response more precisely.
So I hope you like these features and you will test it by yourself because this features
are really perfect for some quick discussions, questions and creative thinking.
So try use it next time when you want to explore a new topic or qualify some podium concept
and you will be surprised how natural and productive it will feel.
Okay, see you in the next lesson.